{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Are there policies and procedures to ensure compliance with applicable legislative, regulatory and contractual requirements?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore is compliant with applicable legislative, regulatory and contractual requirements which are covered through the 'Information Security Context, requirements and scope' document. The policy is reviewed and updated at least once annually.",
      "theme": "Compliance & Legal",
      "subTheme": "Compliance and legal",
      "id": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": "3",
      "theme": "CSR (Ethics,anti-bribery,anti-corruption...)",
      "subTheme": "CSR (Ethics,anti-bribery,anti-corruption...)",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does VERMEG require its employees to complete ethics/fraud awareness anti-bribery and corruption training?",
      "answer": "VERMEG has a formally documented and approved Anti-Bribery policy and Ethic policy which are reviewed regularly. VERMEG's Anti Bribery Policy and VERMEG Ethic policy are used by VERMEG Academy as support for New Joiners compulsory Training."
    },
    {
      "id": "4",
      "theme": "Incident Management",
      "subTheme": "Incident Management",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does your organization have a formal Incident Management program in place? / Does your organization have a formal Incident Management program in place?",
      "answer": "VERMEG has a security incident management procedure in place with defined roles and responsibilities, including a documented plan of identification, response, escalation and resolution of incidents. / VERMEG has a security incident management procedure in place with defined roles and responsibilities, including a documented plan of identification, response, escalation and resolution of incidents.",
      "tags": []
    },
    {
      "id": "5",
      "theme": "Change Management",
      "subTheme": "Change Management",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you have a formally documented change control process?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore has a formally documented Change Management procedure including required approvals and oversight to manage organizational changes. The Change management workflow is implemented in JIRA tool."
    },
    {
      "id": "6",
      "theme": "Business Continuity",
      "subTheme": "BCP",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does your organization have a Business Continuity (BCP) Program in place?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore has a Business Continuity Plan which is formally documented and approved by senior management. It is reviewed and updated at least once per year."
    },
    {
      "id": "7",
      "theme": "Human Resources",
      "subTheme": "Human Ressources",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Screening, background check, Background vetting, Background verification?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore implements a formal and documented Screening procedure: Background verification checks on all candidates for employment are carried out in accordance with relevant laws, regulations and ethics."
    },
    {
      "id": "8",
      "theme": "Risk Management",
      "subTheme": "Risk Management",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you document and apply an information security risk treatment process? / Do you document and apply an information security risk treatment process?",
      "answer": "VERMEG has a formally documented, defined and implemented risk management process described in the document 'VERMEG Risk Management Methodology' in compliance with ISO 27005. It is reviewed and updated on an annual basis. / VERMEG has a formally documented, defined and implemented risk management process described in the document 'VERMEG Risk Management Methodology' in compliance with ISO 27005. It is reviewed and updated on an annual basis.",
      "tags": []
    },
    {
      "id": "9",
      "theme": "Personal Data (e.g GDPR)",
      "subTheme": "Personal Data (e.g GDPR)",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Has a Data Protection Policy been defined, and is there a formal proof of the adoption of the Policy by Senior Management?",
      "answer": "VERMEG has two related policies for Data protection scope: 'Privacy and Data Protection Policy' and 'GDPR Controller Processor Agreement Policy'. They are formally documented and approved by senior management. Also reviewed and updated on a yearly basis."
    },
    {
      "id": "10",
      "theme": "Software Security",
      "subTheme": "Software Security",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you separate testing & operational facilities? Are test and development users restricted from accessing systems containing production data?",
      "answer": "The separation between the development, testing, and operational environments exists to reduce the risks of unauthorized access or changes to the operational environment and it is necessary for a smooth and secure operation of activities. The related VERMEG controls are defined in an appropriate process: 'Access control Procedure'."
    },
    {
      "id": "11",
      "theme": "Physical Security",
      "subTheme": "Physical Security",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does your organization have procedure to prevent unauthorized physical access?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore has a physical and environmental procedure which is formally documented and approved and conforming to ISO 27001 available within 'VERMEG Information Security Procedure'."
    },
    {
      "id": "12",
      "theme": "Encryption",
      "subTheme": "Encryption",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you have policy for cryptographic controls?",
      "answer": "A policy on the use of cryptographic controls for protection of information to secure services is implemented in VERMEG. It is formally documented and approved by the senior management, and updated on a regular basis (at least once per year)."
    },
    {
      "id": "13",
      "theme": "Network",
      "subTheme": "Network",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Are vulnerability & penetration tests performed on internal and external facing networks & systems?",
      "answer": "VERMEG's annual vulnerability assessments, scans and penetration tests are performed on both internal and external facing networks & systems. VERMEG collaborates with External Third party companies for the applications' vulnerability scans."
    },
    {
      "id": "14",
      "theme": "Vulnerability Management",
      "subTheme": "Vulnerability Management",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Is a formal vulnerability and patch management program in place to ensure application, system, and network device vulnerabilities are evaluated, and patches applied in a timely manner?",
      "answer": "VERMEG uses a vulnerability management programme whereby software vulnerabilities are identified via static code analysis using Veracode SAST. Vulnerabilities in the client facing environments are identified using Rapid7 vulnerability management software. VERMEG support evaluate and fix vulnerabilities in the order of severity."
    },
    {
      "question": "Does your organization have a data backup processes and any off-site storage arrangements? / Does your organization have a data backup processes and any off-site storage arrangements?",
      "answer": "Backup/restoration appropriate procedure is defined, maintained and continually tested in VERMEGBIWA, 'Backup and restore procedure'. / Backup/restoration appropriate procedure is defined, maintained and continually tested in VERMEGBIWA, 'Backup and restore procedure'.",
      "id": "15",
      "tags": []
    },
    {
      "id": "366410",
      "theme": "Governance",
      "subTheme": "Governance",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Has the information security policy been approved by senior management? / Has the information security policy been approved by senior management?",
      "answer": "VERMEG's Information Security and all subordinate policies have been approved by senior management. The Information Security Policy is signed by VERMEG CEO, reviewed at least once a year and communicated to interested parties. / VERMEG's Information Security and all subordinate policies have been approved by senior management. The Information Security Policy is signed by VERMEG CEO, reviewed at least once a year and communicated to interested parties.",
      "tags": []
    },
    {
      "id": "590481",
      "theme": "Compliance & Legal",
      "subTheme": "Compliance and legal",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Are there policies and procedures to ensure compliance with applicable legislative, regulatory and contractual requirements?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore is compliant with applicable legislative, regulatory and contractual requirements which are covered through the 'Information Security Context, requirements and scope' document. The policy is reviewed and updated at least once annually."
    },
    {
      "id": "734997",
      "theme": "CSR (Ethics,anti-bribery,anti-corruption...)",
      "subTheme": "CSR (Ethics,anti-bribery,anti-corruption...)",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does VERMEG require its employees to complete ethics/fraud awareness anti-bribery and corruption training?",
      "answer": "VERMEG has a formally documented and approved Anti-Bribery policy and Ethic policy which are reviewed regularly. VERMEG's Anti Bribery Policy and VERMEG Ethic policy are used by VERMEG Academy as support for New Joiners compulsory Training."
    },
    {
      "id": "527008",
      "theme": "Change Management",
      "subTheme": "Change Management",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you have a formally documented change control process?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore has a formally documented Change Management procedure including required approvals and oversight to manage organizational changes. The Change management workflow is implemented in JIRA tool."
    },
    {
      "id": "233843",
      "theme": "Business Continuity",
      "subTheme": "BCP",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does your organization have a Business Continuity (BCP) Program in place?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore has a Business Continuity Plan which is formally documented and approved by senior management. It is reviewed and updated at least once per year."
    },
    {
      "id": "761810",
      "theme": "Human Resources",
      "subTheme": "Human Ressources",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Screening, background check, Background vetting, Background verification?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore implements a formal and documented Screening procedure: Background verification checks on all candidates for employment are carried out in accordance with relevant laws, regulations and ethics."
    },
    {
      "id": "214756",
      "theme": "Personal Data (e.g GDPR)",
      "subTheme": "Personal Data (e.g GDPR)",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Has a Data Protection Policy been defined, and is there a formal proof of the adoption of the Policy by Senior Management?",
      "answer": "VERMEG has two related policies for Data protection scope: 'Privacy and Data Protection Policy' and 'GDPR Controller Processor Agreement Policy'. They are formally documented and approved by senior management. Also reviewed and updated on a yearly basis."
    },
    {
      "id": "423428",
      "theme": "Software Security",
      "subTheme": "Software Security",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you separate testing & operational facilities? Are test and development users restricted from accessing systems containing production data?",
      "answer": "The separation between the development, testing, and operational environments exists to reduce the risks of unauthorized access or changes to the operational environment and it is necessary for a smooth and secure operation of activities. The related VERMEG controls are defined in an appropriate process: 'Access control Procedure'."
    },
    {
      "id": "791956",
      "theme": "Physical Security",
      "subTheme": "Physical Security",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Does your organization have procedure to prevent unauthorized physical access?",
      "answer": "VERMEG is certified ISO 27001, therefore has a physical and environmental procedure which is formally documented and approved and conforming to ISO 27001 available within 'VERMEG Information Security Procedure'."
    },
    {
      "id": "328094",
      "theme": "Encryption",
      "subTheme": "Encryption",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Do you have policy for cryptographic controls?",
      "answer": "A policy on the use of cryptographic controls for protection of information to secure services is implemented in VERMEG. It is formally documented and approved by the senior management, and updated on a regular basis (at least once per year)."
    },
    {
      "id": "800502",
      "theme": "Governance",
      "subTheme": "Governance",
      "category": "-",
      "question": "Has the information security policy been approved by senior management?",
      "answer": "VERMEG's Information Security and all subordinate policies have been approved by senior management. The Information Security Policy is signed by VERMEG CEO, reviewed at least once a year and communicated to interested parties."
    },
    {
      "id": "1",
      "question": "Sample flagged question",
      "user_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": "a142",
      "question": "What is vermeg ?",
      "answer": "Vermeg is a .....",
      "theme": "Encryption",
      "subTheme": "Encryption"
    },
    {
      "id": "d67f",
      "question": "Are there policies and procedures to ensure compliance with applicable legislative,",
      "answer": "Yes",
      "theme": "Compliance & Legal",
      "subTheme": "Compliance and legal"
    }
  ],
  "themes": [
    {
      "id": "1",
      "name": "Governance"
    },
    {
      "id": "2",
      "name": "Compliance & Legal"
    },
    {
      "id": "3",
      "name": "CSR (Ethics,anti-bribery,anti-corruption...)"
    },
    {
      "id": "4",
      "name": "Incident Management"
    },
    {
      "id": "5",
      "name": "Change Management"
    },
    {
      "id": "6",
      "name": "Business Continuity"
    },
    {
      "id": "7",
      "name": "Human Resources"
    },
    {
      "id": "8",
      "name": "Risk Management"
    },
    {
      "id": "9",
      "name": "Personal Data (e.g GDPR)"
    },
    {
      "id": "10",
      "name": "Software Security"
    },
    {
      "id": "11",
      "name": "Physical Security"
    },
    {
      "id": "12",
      "name": "Encryption"
    },
    {
      "id": "13",
      "name": "Network"
    },
    {
      "id": "14",
      "name": "Vulnerability Management"
    },
    {
      "id": "15",
      "name": "Logs and Backup"
    }
  ],
  "subThemes": [
    {
      "id": "1",
      "name": "Governance",
      "themeId": "1"
    },
    {
      "id": "2",
      "name": "Compliance and legal",
      "themeId": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": "3",
      "name": "CSR (Ethics,anti-bribery,anti-corruption...)",
      "themeId": "3"
    },
    {
      "id": "4",
      "name": "Incident Management",
      "themeId": "4"
    },
    {
      "id": "5",
      "name": "Change Management",
      "themeId": "5"
    },
    {
      "id": "6",
      "name": "BCP",
      "themeId": "6"
    },
    {
      "id": "7",
      "name": "Human Ressources",
      "themeId": "7"
    },
    {
      "id": "8",
      "name": "Risk Management",
      "themeId": "8"
    },
    {
      "id": "9",
      "name": "Personal Data (e.g GDPR)",
      "themeId": "9"
    },
    {
      "id": "10",
      "name": "Software Security",
      "themeId": "10"
    },
    {
      "id": "11",
      "name": "Physical Security",
      "themeId": "11"
    },
    {
      "id": "12",
      "name": "Encryption",
      "themeId": "12"
    },
    {
      "id": "13",
      "name": "Network",
      "themeId": "13"
    },
    {
      "id": "14",
      "name": "Vulnerability Management",
      "themeId": "14"
    },
    {
      "id": "15",
      "name": "Logs and Backup",
      "themeId": "15"
    }
  ],
  "categories": [
    {
      "id": "1",
      "name": "Governance",
      "subThemeId": "1"
    },
    {
      "id": "2",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": "3",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "3"
    },
    {
      "id": "4",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "4"
    },
    {
      "id": "5",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "5"
    },
    {
      "id": "6",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "6"
    },
    {
      "id": "7",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "7"
    },
    {
      "id": "8",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "8"
    },
    {
      "id": "9",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "9"
    },
    {
      "id": "10",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "10"
    },
    {
      "id": "11",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "11"
    },
    {
      "id": "12",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "12"
    },
    {
      "id": "13",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "13"
    },
    {
      "id": "14",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "14"
    },
    {
      "id": "15",
      "name": "-",
      "subThemeId": "15"
    }
  ],
  "flaggedQuestions": [
    {
      "id": "11c8",
      "question": "hhhh",
      "user_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": "9ccb",
      "question": "Why is Vermeg ",
      "user_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": "f6eb",
      "question": "how",
      "user_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "id": "8739",
      "question": "How to secure my data "
    },
    {
      "id": "c61b",
      "question": "Test1"
    }
  ],
  "users": [
    {
      "id": "1",
      "name": "Admin",
      "email": "admin@gmail.com",
      "password": "123456",
      "role": "admin"
    },
    {
      "id": "2",
      "name": "User",
      "email": "user@gmail.com",
      "password": "123456",
      "role": "user"
    },
    {
      "id": "3",
      "name": "User2",
      "email": "user2@gmail.com",
      "password": "123456",
      "role": "user"
    },
    {
      "id": "4",
      "name": "Admin2",
      "email": "admin2@gmail.com",
      "password": "123456",
      "role": "admin"
    }
  ]
}